Guide to the Elizabeth Robins Papers 1803-1963 MSS 002
Fales Library and Special Collections
- Series VII: Literary Productions
  - Both Sides of the Curtain, (ca. 1939)
    - Chapter 32 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 33 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 34 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Chapters 35-39 MS/TS (Box 12, Folder 33)
    - Chapters 40-42 MS/TS (Box 13, Folder 34)
    - Chapters 43-47 MS/TS (Box 13, Folder 35)
    - Chapters 48-50 MS/TS (Box 13, Folder 36)
    - "Introductory" TS (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Chapter l--"The First Years" TS (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Chapter 2 - "Oscar Wilde to the Rescue" TS (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Chapters 4-6 TS (Box 14, Folder 40)
    - Chapters 7-10 TS (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Chapter 11 TS (Box 14, Folder 42)
    - Chapter 12 TS (Box 14, Folder 43)
    - Chapters 13-17 TS (Box 14, Folder 44)
    - Chapter 18 TS (Box 14, Folder 45)
    - Chapters 19-21 TS (Box 14, Folder 46)
    - Chapter 23 TS (Box 14, Folder 47)
    - Chapters 24-26 TS (Box 14, Folder 48)
    - Chapter 27 TS (Box 14, Folder 49)
    - Chapter 28 TS (Box 14, Folder 50)
    - Chapter 29 TS (Box 14, Folder 51)
    - Chapter 30 TS (Box 14, Folder 52)
    - Chapter 31 TS (Box 14, Folder 53)
    - Chapter 32 TS (Box 14, Folder 54)
    - Chapter 33 TS (Box 15, Folder 55)
    - Chapter 34 TS (Box 15, Folder 56)
    - "Appendix" TS (Box 15, Folder 57)
    - Fragments ("bits") TS (Box 15, Folder 58)
    - First carbon--chapters 1-13 TS (Box 16, Folder 59)
    - First carbon--chapter 18 TS (Box 16, Folder 60)
    - Second carbon - chapters 1-10 TS (Box 16, Folder 61)
    - Second carbon - chapters 12-16 TS (Box 16, Folder 62)
    - Carbons/originals--chapters 17-20 TS (Box 16, Folder 63)
    - Carbon--unnumbered chapter TS (Box 16, Folder 64)
    - Notes (ER's and William Archer's) MS/TS (Box 17, Folder 65)
    - Notes re: George Bernard Shaw MS/TS (Box 17, Folder 66)
    - Correspondence, 1939 -1940 (Box 17, Folder 67)
      See also Oversize Material, Box 3, Folder 4 for an Index, possibly to Both Sides of the Curtain.
  - The Bowarra, (1909?)
    - Pages 1-40 MS (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Pages 1-60 MS (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Act I, scenes II and III MS (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Act II, scenes I and II MS (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Notes and TS annotated by Granville Barker (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Act I, scenes I-III TS (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Notes MS (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - Scenario TS (Box 18, Folder 8)
    - Act I TS (Box 18, Folder 9)
    - Act I, scenes II-IV TS (Box 18, Folder 10)
    - Act II, scenes I-VI TS (Box 18, Folder 11)
    - Act II, scenes I-VI TS (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Fragments TS (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence--Granville Barker, 1909 -1910 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence, 1908 -1910 (Box 18, Folder 15)
      Includes William Archer, Florence Bell, Herbert Beerbohm Tree.
  - Camilla
    - Part I, chapter 1 MS (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - "Nancarrow" MS (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - "Michael's Ambassadress" MS (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - "A Different Nancarrow" MS (Box 19, Folder 4)
    - The Sand Spur" MS (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - "The Arraignment" MS (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - "Church and Law" MS (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - "Alice" MS (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - "Leroy" MS (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - "An Engagement and a Telegram" MS (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Home and School," "Enter Leroy" MS (Box 19, Folder 11)
    - Untitled chapter MS (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - "Easter" MS (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - "Vandewater's Landing" MS (Box 19, Folder 14)
    - "America Again" MS (Box 19, Folder 15)
    - "The Vision" MS (Box 19, Folder 16)
    - "His Father" MS (Box 19, Folder 17)
    - "The End" MS (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - "Engaged" MS (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - "The Best of all Letter" MS (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Untitled chapter MS (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - "Sister Julia Delivers a Telephone Message" MS (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - "Linda" MS (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - "Marriage" MS (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "Crossing with Leroy" MS (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - "The End of the Voyage" MS (Box 19, Folder 26)
    - "The Tango" MS (Box 19, Folder 27)
    - "Marriott's Visit" MS (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - "Hilltop" MS (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - "The Cave" MS (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - "Lost" MS (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - "Found" MS (Box 20, Folder 32)
    - Alternate beginning (Based on Sisson's suggestions) MS (Box 20, Folder 33)
    - Notes MS (Box 20, Folder 34)
    - Part I, chapters 1-10 TS (Box 21, Folder 35)
    - Part I, chapters 11-16 TS (Box 21, Folder 36)
    - Part II, chapters 1-11 TS (Box 21, Folder 37)
    - Part II, chapters 12-20 TS (Box 21, Folder 38)
    - [Preface by Octavia Wilberforce?] MS (Box 21, Folder 39)
  - A Close up View of Queen Victoria and the English Stage
    See An American Actress at Balmoral Castle
  - Come and Find Me, (1906)
    - Chapters 1-11 TS (Box 22, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 12-22 TS (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 23-26 TS (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Chapter Fragments (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Film Synopsis TS (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Florence Bell letter, June 5, 1906 (Box 22, Folder 6)
  - The Convert
    - Chapters 1-10 TS (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 11-18 TS (Box 23, Folder 2)
  - The Dark Latern, (1905)
    - Part II, chapters 1-11 MS (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Part II, chapters 12-20 MS (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Part II, Chapters 21-24 MS (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Parts I and II, assorted chapters MS (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Book I, "The Prologue" TS (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Book II, "Dr. Vincent" TS (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Book III TS (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Book IV TS (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - TS (incomplete) (Box 25, Folder 9-10)
    - Correspondence, 1905 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Dramatization (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Discretion
    - MS for play (Box 26, Folder 1-2)
    - MS for short story, pages 1-35 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - TS for short story (Box 26, Folder 4-5)
    - Correspondence, 1912 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Evangeline, (ca. 1914)
    - Act I MS (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Act II MS (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Act III MS (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Act IV MS (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Notes MS (Box 27, Folder 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1914 -1915 (Box 27, Folder 7)
  - Fear
    See The Secret that was Kept
  - The Florentine Frame
    - Acts I-III MS (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Fragments MS (Box 28, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 1-14 TS (Box 28, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 15 MS (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 16-20 (marked 15-19) (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 1-3 - TS (Box 28, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 4-13 TS (Box 28, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 14-end TS (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - The Friend of Women
    See Votes for Women
  - Go to Sleep Stories, (ca. 1905)
    - Manuscript/typescript and notes (Box 29, Folder 1-2)
    - Notes (Box 29, Folder 3)
    - The Cave of the Wicked MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 4)
    - "The Devilman at Last!" MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 5)
    - "The Importance of Buttons" MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 6)
    - "King Salmon" MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 7)
    - "How to Move an Island" MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 8)
    - "The Adlets" MS (Box 30, Folder 9)
    - Chapter fragments MS/TS (Box 30, Folder 10)
    - Bits out of (original) "m e Funeral" MS (Box 30, Folder 11)
    - Preface and Synopsis TS (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - "The Stolen Wife" TS (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - "Where the Lost Needles Go" TS (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - "An Interlude" TS (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - "The Importance of Buttons" TS (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - "The Funeral" TS (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "The Old Woman who Lived in a Volcano TS (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - "King Salmon" TS (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - "The Orphan," "Big Premorska," "One who is not seen Anymore," "The Funeral" TS (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - "The Crow's Feather" TS (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Preface TS (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - #1 "The Stolen Wife" TS (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - #2 "Where the Lost Needles Go" TS (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - #3 "Interlude" TS (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - #3 "One who is not seen Anymore" TS (Box 32, Folder 26)
    - #4 "The Funeral" TS (Box 32, Folder 27)
    - #4 "The Importance of Buttons" TS (Box 32, Folder 28)
    - #5 "The Old Woman who Lived in a Volcano" TS (Box 32, Folder 29)
    - #6 "The Adlet People" TS (Box 32, Folder 30)
    - #7 "King Salmon" TS (Box 32, Folder 31)
    - #8 "The Cave of the Wicked" TS (Box 32, Folder 32)
    - #9 "The Devilman at Last!" TS (Box 32, Folder 33)
    - #10 "The Whale's Revenge" TS (Box 32, Folder 34)
    - #11 "Little Issara" TS (Box 32, Folder 35)
    - #12 "How to Move an Island" TS (Box 32, Folder 36)
    - #13 "The Winning of Nancheet" TS (Box 32, Folder 37)
    - Preface TS (Box 33, Folder 38)
    - #1 "The Stolen Wife" TS (Box 33, Folder 39)
    - #2 'where the Lost Needles Go" TS (Box 33, Folder 40)
    - #3 "Interlude" TS (Box 33, Folder 41)
    - #4 "The Importance of Buttons" TS (Box 33, Folder 42)
    - #5 "The Old Woman who Lived in a Volcano" TS (Box 33, Folder 43)
    - #6 "The Adlet People" TS (Box 33, Folder 44)
    - #7 "King Salmon" TS (Box 33, Folder 45)
    - #8 "The Cave of the Wicked" TS (Box 33, Folder 46)
    - #9 "The Devilman at Last!" TS (Box 33, Folder 47)
    - #10 "The Whale's Revenge" TS (Box 33, Folder 48)
    - #11 "Little Issara" TS (Box 33, Folder 49)
    - #12 "How to Move an Island" TS (Box 33, Folder 50)
    - #13 "The Winning of Nancheet" TS (Box 33, Folder 51)
    - One letter, August 8, 1905 (Box 33, Folder 52)
  - Judith
  - Kenyon and his Daughter, (1930)
    See Rocky Mountain Journal
  - The Magnetic North
    - Winter Camp on the Yukon (Box 34, Folder 1)
    - "The House Warming" (Box 34, Folder 2)
    - "Two New Spissimens" (Box 34, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 5: "The Blow Out" (Box 34, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 6 (Box 34, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 7: "A Penetential Journey" (Box 34, Folder 6)
    - "Christmas" (Box 34, Folder 7)
    - "A Christian Agnostic" (Box 34, Folder 8)
    - "Princess Muckluck" (Box 34, Folder 9)
    - "The Great White Silence" (Box 34, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 12 (Box 34, Folder 11)
    - "The Esquimaux Horse" (Box 34, Folder 12)
    - "Monica's Village" (Box 35, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 16 (Box 35, Folder 14)
    - "The Cabin is Cold" (Box 35, Folder 15)
    - Untitled chapters (Box 35, Folder 16)
    - "The Ice Goes Out" (Box 35, Folder 17)
    - "The Klondyke" (Box 35, Folder 18)
    - "Where they Found the Gold" (Box 35, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 1: "Winter Camp on the Yukon" MS (Box 36, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 2: "The House Warming" MS (Box 36, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 3: "Two New Spissimens" MS (Box 36, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 4: "The Blow Out" MS (Box 36, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 5: "The Shawman" MS (Box 36, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 6: "The Penitential Journey" MS (Box 36, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 7: "Kaviak's Crime" MS (Box 36, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 8: "Christmas" MS (Box 36, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 9: "A Christian Agnostic" MS (Box 36, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 10: "Princess Muckluck MS (Box 36, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 11: "Holy Cross" MS (Box 36, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 12: "The Great White Silence" MS (Box 36, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 13: "The Pit" MS (Box 36, Folder 32)
    - Chapter 14: "Kurilla" MS (Box 36, Folder 33)
    - Chapter 15: "The Esquimaux Horse" MS (Box 36, Folder 34)
    - Chapter 16: "Minook" MS (Box 36, Folder 35)
    - Chapter 17: "The Great Stampede" MS (Box 36, Folder 36)
    - Chapter 18: "A Miner's Meeting" MS (Box 36, Folder 37)
    - Chapter 19: "The Ice Goes Out" MS (Box 36, Folder 38)
    - Chapter 20: "The Klondyke" MS (Box 36, Folder 39)
    - Chapter 21 MS (Box 37, Folder 40)
    - Chapter 22: "The Going Home" MS (Box 37, Folder 41)
    - "The Cabin is Cold" MS (Box 37, Folder 42)
    - "A Red Hot Roarin' Boom" MS (Box 37, Folder 43)
    - Untitled chapter ("To be inserted") MS (Box 37, Folder 44)
    - "On the Way to Anvik" TS (Box 37, Folder 45)
    - Notes MS (Box 37, Folder 46-47)
    - Fragment MS (Box 37, Folder 48)
    - Maud's 1891 Alaska diary, used as source (Box 37, Folder 49)
  - The Messenger, (1917)
    - Chapters 1-5 MS (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 6-10 MS (Box 38, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 11-20 MS (Box 38, Folder 3)
    - Chapters 21-32 (incomplete) MS (Box 38, Folder 4)
    - Chapters 1-7 TS (Box 39, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 8-12 TS (Box 39, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 13-16 TS (Box 39, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 17-20, 23, 24 TS (Box 39, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 25 TS/MS (Box 39, Folder 9)
    - Chapters 26-31 TS (Box 39, Folder 10)
    - Chapters 32-36 TS (Box 39, Folder 11)
    - Pages 1-102 TS (Box 40, Folder 12)
    - Pages 104-342 TS (Box 40, Folder 13)
    - Chapters 28-30, 32 (or F-H, J) TS (Box 40, Folder 14)
    - "Remnants after cutting for serial" TS (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Chapters 1-13, carbon TS (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Chapters 14-20, carbon TS (Box 40, Folder 17)
    - Chapters 1-5, carbon TS (Box 40, Folder 18)
    - Chapters 6-12, carbon TS (Box 40, Folder 19)
    - Chapter fragments TS/MS (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Notes MS (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Notes and newspaper clippings (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Correspondence, 1916 -1917 (Box 41, Folder 23)
      Including Florence Bell, William Archer.
  - The Mills of the Gods
    - MS (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 1-4 TS (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Chapters 5-8 TS (Box 42, Folder 3)
  - Mirkwater
    - Acts I and II MS (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Act III (written by ER and William Archer) MS (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Act I TS (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Acts I-III TS (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Act I TS (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Act II TS (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Act III TS (Box 43, Folder 7)
  - My Little Sister
    Where are You Going to?
  - The Open Question, (1887)
    - Dedication TS/MS, 1907 (Box 44, Folder 1)
    - Chapter 1 MS (Box 44, Folder 2)
    - Chapter 2 MS (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Chapter 3 MS (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Chapter 3, fragments MS (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 4 MS (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Chapter 5 MS (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 6 MS (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Chapter 7 MS (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 8 MS (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 9 MS (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 10 MS (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 11 MS (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 12 MS (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 13 MS (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 14 MS (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 15 MS (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 17 MS (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - Chapter 16 MS (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Chapter 18 MS (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Chapter 19 MS (Box 44, Folder 21)
    - Chapter 20 MS (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Chapter 21 MS (Box 45, Folder 23)
    - Chapter 22 MS (Box 45, Folder 24)
    - Chapter 23 MS/TS (Box 45, Folder 25)
    - Chapter 24 MS (Box 45, Folder 26)
    - Chapter 25 MS (Box 45, Folder 27)
    - Chapter 26 MS (Box 45, Folder 28)
    - Chapter 27 MS (Box 45, Folder 29)
    - Chapter 28 MS (Box 45, Folder 30)
    - Chapter 30 MS (Box 45, Folder 31)
    - Chapter 31 MS (Box 45, Folder 32)
    - Chapter 32 MS (Box 45, Folder 33)
    - Chapter 33 MS (Box 45, Folder 34)
    - Chapter 33, fragments MS (Box 45, Folder 35)
    - Chapter 34 MS (Box 45, Folder 36)
    - Chapter 34, fragments MS (Box 45, Folder 37)
    - Chapter 35 MS (Box 45, Folder 38)
    - Chapter 36 MS (Box 45, Folder 39)
    - Chapter 37 MS (Box 45, Folder 40)
    - Final Chapter MS/TS (Box 45, Folder 41)
    - Fragments MS (Box 45, Folder 42)
    - Chapters 1-2 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 43)
    - Chapters 3-4 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 44)
    - Chapter 5 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 45)
    - Chapter 6 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 46)
    - Chapter 7 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 47)
    - Chapters 8-9 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 48)
    - Chapter 10 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 49)
    - Chapters 11-12 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 50)
    - Chapter 13 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 51)
    - Chapter 14 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 52)
    - Chapter 15 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 53)
    - Chapter 16 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 54)
    - Chapter 17 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 55)
    - Chapter 18 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 56)
    - Chapter 19 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 57)
    - Chapter 20 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 58)
    - Chapter 21 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 59)
    - Chapter 22 TS w/annotation (Box 46, Folder 60)
    - Description of book (fragment) MS (Box 46, Folder 61)
  - The Pleiades, (1914)
    - Chapters 1-5 MS (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Chapters 6-12 MS (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Unnumbered chapters MS (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Unnumbered chapters MS (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Notes MS (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - Chapters 1-6 TS (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Chapters 7-15 TS (Box 48, Folder 7)
    - Chapters 16-22 TS (Box 48, Folder 8)
  - Raymond and I
    - Notes MS (Box 49, Folder 1-5)
    - Notes--typescripts from diaries and letters (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Introductory TS, 1932 (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Pages 1-135 TS (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - "Kaiomi" TS (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - "After Goodbye" TS (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - "Living Under Martial Law" TS (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - "The Court Arrives" TS (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence, 1939 -1955 (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Rocky Mountain Journal, [1949?]
    - Kenyon and His Daughter MS (Box 50, Folder 1-4)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Notes MS (Box 50, Folder 5-6)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Notes MS (Box 51, Folder 7-9)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Notes, fragments TS (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part I TS (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part II TS (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part III TS (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part IV TS (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part V TS (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI, chapters 1-9 TS (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI, chapters 10-15 TS (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI, chapter 16 (1930) TS (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI, chapters 17-19 TS (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part I TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part II TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part III TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 22)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part I TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 23)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part II TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 24)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part III TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 25)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part IV TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 26)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part V TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 27)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI chapters 1-9 TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 28)
    - Kenyon and His Daughter, Part VI chapters 10-16 TS (carbon) (Box 53, Folder 29)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, fragment MS/TS (Box 54, Folder 30)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part I TS (Box 54, Folder 31)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part II TS (Box 54, Folder 32)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part III TS (Box 54, Folder 33)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part IV TS (Box 54, Folder 34)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part V TS (Box 54, Folder 35)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part VI TS (Box 54, Folder 36)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part VII TS (Box 54, Folder 37)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Part VIII TS (Box 54, Folder 38)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Parts I-III TS (carbon) (Box 55, Folder 39)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Parts IV-VI TS (carbon) (Box 55, Folder 40)
    - Rocky Mountain Journal, Parts VII, VIII TS (carbon) (Box 55, Folder 41)
  - Scenes Behind the Scenes, [1895?]
    - Rough draft MS (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Pages 1-25 and fragments MS (Box 56, Folder 2)
    - "How to Succeed on the Stage" MS (Box 56, Folder 3)
    - "A Manager's Mistake" MS (Box 56, Folder 4)
    - "The Imaginative Writer" MS (Box 56, Folder 5)
    - "The Bellerieuse" MS (Box 56, Folder 6)
    - #1 "A Manager's Mistake" TS (Box 56, Folder 7)
    - #3 "A Highly Respectable Heroine" TS (Box 56, Folder 8)
    - #4 "Miss MacMurdo Interviews Her Patron" TS (Box 56, Folder 9)
    - "Miss MacMurdo Decides to Go on the Stage" TS (Box 56, Folder 10)
    - #1, #3 TS (carbon) (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - The Secret that was Kept
    - Fear, a condensed account in multiple copies TS (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Fear, synopsis TS (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - Fear, or The Secret that was Kept, synopsis TS (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - Fear, or The Secret that was Kept MS (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Fear, or The Secret that was Kept, notes MS (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - Fear, or The Secret that was Kept, as a play in 3 acts TS (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Fear, or the Secret that was Kept, chapters 4-6 TS (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - The Secret that was Kept, fragments TS (Box 57, Folder 8)
    - The Secret that was Kept, incomplete TS (Box 58, Folder 9-10)
  - The Short Cut
    - MS (Box 59, Folder 1)
    - TS (Box 59, Folder 2)
    - TS, "Duplicate copy" (Box 59, Folder 3)
    - Fragments and notes MS/TS (Box 59, Folder 4)
  - The Silver Lotus (A Play in Three Acts)
    - Act I MS (Box 60, Folder 1)
    - Act II MS (Box 60, Folder 2)
    - Act III MS (Box 60, Folder 3)
    - Act I TS (Box 60, Folder 4)
    - Act II TS (Box 60, Folder 5)
    - Act III TS (Box 60, Folder 6)
  - A Study in Egoism
    See Theodora or the Pilgrimage
  - Theatre and Friendship
    - Preface, duplicate copies TS (Box 61, Folder 1)
    - Pages 1-57 TS (Box 61, Folder 2)
    - Preface-page 102 TS (Box 61, Folder 3)
    - Pages 103-199 TS (Box 61, Folder 4)
    - Pages 200-307 TS (Box 61, Folder 5)
    - Chapter 18, appendix TS (Box 61, Folder 6)
    - Letter transcriptions: Henry James to ER (1 of 3) TS (Box 61, Folder 7-9)
    - Notes, letter transcriptions: Henry James to ER MS/TS (Box 61, Folder 10)
    - Letter transcriptions: Henry James to Florence Bell TS (Box 61, Folder 11)
    - Notes MS/TS (Box 61, Folder 12-14)
    - Correspondence--Earl H. Balch (G.P. Putnam's Sons), 1932 (Box 62, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence--Marie Belloc Lowndes, 1932 (Box 62, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence--Victor Gollancz (Victor Gollancz, LTD), 1931 -1932 (Box 62, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence--G. Wren Howard (Jonathan Cape LTD), 1932 (Box 62, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence--General, 1931-32 (Box 62, Folder 19)
  - Theodora or the Pilgrimage, (1910)
    - A Study in Egoism, Chapters 1-6 MS (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - A Study in Egoism, Chapters 7-12 MS (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - A Study in Egoism, Chapters 13-17 MS (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - A Study in Egoism, Chapters 18, 19 MS (Box 63, Folder 4)
    - [Theodora or The Pilgrimage?], notes MS (Box 63, Folder 5)
    - "Theo Book" notes MS (Box 64, Folder 6)
    - "Theo Book" Dedication (1911) and letter from Florence Bell (n.d.) TS (Box 64, Folder 7)
    - "Theo Book" MS (Box 64, Folder 8)
    - "Theo Book" TS (Box 64, Folder 9)
    - Theodora or The Pilgrimage, notes MS 16. Theodora or The Pilgrimage, "Bits" and typed copy MS, TS (Box 65, Folder 10-16)
    - Theodora or The Pilgrimage, chapters 1-9 TS (Box 66, Folder 17)
    - Theodora or The Pilgrimage, chapters 10-16 TS (Box 66, Folder 18)
    - Theodora or The Pilgrimage, chapters 1-9 TS (carbon) (Box 66, Folder 19)
    - Theodora or The Pilgrimage, chapters 10-19 TS (carbon) (Box 66, Folder 20)
  - Time is Whispering
    - Judith, notes (Box 67, Folder 1)
    - Judith, notes (Box 67, Folder 2)
    - Autumn, chapters 1-6 MS (Box 67, Folder 3)
    - Autumn, chapters 7-12 MS (Box 67, Folder 4)
    - Autumn, chapters 13-20 MS (Box 67, Folder 5)
    - Autumn, chapters 21-22, unnumbered, 23 MS (Box 67, Folder 6)
    - Autumn, ten unnumbered chapters MS (Box 68, Folder 7)
    - Autumn, chapters 1-5 TS (Box 68, Folder 8)
    - Autumn, chapters 6-10 TS (Box 68, Folder 9)